个人原创字幕
制作人：埃里克
-那招杀死他了吗？  -没有
-Did that kill it?  -No.
那个可以杀了他
That, that will kill it.
维山帝之书
The Book of Vishanti!
我们不能让它夺走你的能力
We can't let it take your power!
快去拿书！
Get to the book!
我们怎么过去？
How do we get across?
跳！
Jump!
它太强大了！
It's too strong!
我控制不住它！
I can't hold it!
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry,
这是唯一的办法了
This is the only way.
你要干什么？
What are you doing?
我不能让那怪物吸走你的能力
I can't let that thing take your power
你自己无法控制它
You can't control it.
但我可以
But I can.
我们是朋友啊
But we're friends.
你却要杀了我！
You're killing me!
我知道
I know.
但是在多元宇宙的宏大演算中
But in the grand calculus of the Multiverse,
你的牺牲比你的生命更有价值
your sacrifice is worth more than your life.
斯特兰奇医生
Doctor Strange.
韦斯特医生
Doctor West
好久不见啊
Haven't seen you in a while.
我化成灰了五年
I was a little preoccupied being dust in the airfor 5 years.
我们好多人也是一样
So were a lot of us.
在我消失期间……
While I was gone...
“谢谢”你的关心
Thank you for asking.
我的两只猫都死了
I lose both my cats.
还有我哥哥
And my brother.
我很遗憾
I'm very sorry.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想，让我在夜里辗转反侧的是这个念头：
I guess what keeps me up at night is wondering...
事情必须以这种方式发生吗？
Did it have to happen that way?
还有别的路可选吗？
Is there any other path?
没有，这是我们唯一的机会
No, but I made the only play we have.
哦，你确实这么干了
Oh, of course you did.
最伟大的外科医生和超级英雄
The best surgeon and the best superhero.
但你还是没能得到这个女孩
But you still didn't get the girl.
请给我来杯红酒
A class of red, please.
请让我来，小姐
Allow me, miss.
是不是闻起来没区别？
A little too on the nose?
怎么，你能来参加我的婚礼
What, for you, at my wedding?
不，我觉得很完美
Nah. It was perfect.
恭喜了
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
那是查理
There's Charlie.
我一定得把他介绍给你，因为他……
I have to introduce you he's kind of,
这有点儿尴尬，但他是你的铁粉
It's embarrassing, but he's a big fan.
克莉丝汀，呃
Christine, umm
我本该……
I should have...
我真希望当初没有那样
I wish it been different.
我一直都在乎着我们俩
I never stopped caring about us.
但我必须做出牺牲
But I have to make sacrifices.
为了保护你
To protect you,
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们俩之间从来没有可能
It was gonna workout between us.
为什么？
Why not?
因为，斯蒂芬
Because Stephen.
你总是想做（手术时）主刀的那一个
You have to be the one holding the knife.
为此，我很敬佩你，但我无法为此爱上你
And I always respected you for it, but I couldn't love you for it.
这句话你藏在心底了多久了？
How long have you had that one in the barrel?
很久了
Long time.
好吧  我想也是
Yeah.  I bet.
真的，我只是……很高兴你能幸福
Truely I'm just...glad you're happy.
我是
I am.
我真的是很快乐
I'm really really am.
你呢？
Are you?
我也很快乐
I'm happy.
那就好
Good.
这是你应得的
You deserve it.
当心！
Look out!
我见过你吗？
Do I know you?
不客气
You are welcome.
你懂不懂要向至尊法师鞠躬行礼的古老习俗啊？
Do you know it's ancient custom to bow in the presence of Sorcerer Supreme?
好了，我现在知道这习俗了
Yeah.  I'm aware of the customs.
真不可思议
That's incredible.
没错
Yeah
她是谁？
Who's this?
我正要问同样的问题  嘿，孩子！
I'm gonna ask the same question.  Hey, kid!
那只怪物想对你做什么？
What did that creature want with you?
你的父母在哪？
Where're your parents?
把她带回圣殿……
Take her back to the Sanctum.
她拿走了我的悬戒
She took my slingy.
她拿走了你的悬戒？
She took your slingy?
我们又不是想害你，孩子
We're not gonna kill you, kid.
我刚刚拼了老命就是为了救你，记得吗？
I just bust my ass trying to save your life, remember?
各种怪兽对我来说不在话下
Giant monsters, I can clearly handle it.
但困扰我的是，昨晚，你出现在了我的梦中
But what bothers me, is that last night, you were in my dream.
那不是一个梦
That, wasn't a dream.
那是在另一个宇宙
There's another universe.
关于多元宇宙，你们有哪些经验？
How much experience you guys have with Multiverse?
对于多元宇宙，我们最近的经验是和蜘蛛侠有关的一件事
We have the experience of the Multiverse most recently was an incident with Spider-Man.
什么“人”？
What man?
蜘蛛“人”
Spider-Man.
他具有蜘蛛的能力
He has the powers of a spider.
因此得名
Hence the name.
好恶心
Gross
他长得像不像蜘蛛？
Does he look like a spider?
不不，更像是个人
No, no, more like a man.
能爬墙，能吐丝
Climbs walls, shoots webs.
是的，没错
Yeah.  Bingo
从屁股吐出来吗？
Out his butt?
不是
No
也许吧，我不知道
Maybe, I don't know.
说实话，希望不是
Honestly, I hope not.
真古怪
Super weird.
你这样（吃东西）会胃疼的
You're gonna get a stomachache.
我是从其他宇宙来的
I'm from another universe.
你怎么能确定咱俩的胃工作方式一样呢？
How do you know my stomach works the same as yours?
我还真不知道
I don't.
我甚至不知道你来自另一个宇宙
I don't even know if you're from another universe,
这就是为啥我还坐在这里等你来解释解释
which is why I'm still sitting here waiting for you to enlighten us.
坦率地说，我认识的两位奇异博士中，
Frankly, of the two Doctor Stranges that I've met,
你不是我最喜欢的
you are not my favorite.
啥意思？
Which means?
他不会说西班牙语？
He can't speak Spanish?
我甚至都不知道他是否喜欢说他的母语
I don't even know if he speaks his own language.
听好了，我刚刚离开了一个美妙的婚礼，
Look, I left a very nice wedding,
就为了救下你个毛孩子不被章鱼吃掉……
to save a smart ass kid from getting eaten by an octopus...
谁的婚礼？
Whose wedding?
告诉我…… 是克莉丝汀的
Tell me...  Christine's.
-你还真去参加了？  -老天爷，你和克莉丝汀结婚了？
-You went?  -Holy shit, you married Christine.
-拍照介意吗？  -是的，我介意
-Do you mind?  -Yes, I do.
不，我没有（结婚）！ 是，我有（去参加婚礼）！
No, I didn't.  Yes!
你得给我解释到底发生了什么
You need to explain to me what's going on.
为什么那只章鱼想吃掉你？
Why was that octopus trying to eat you?
那怪物是想绑架我
That thing was trying to kidnap me
它就像是一个为恶魔工作的小喽罗
It's like a henchman who works for demon.
我只知道，它们想将我的超能力据为己有
All we knew is that they wanted to take my power for themselves.
什么能力？
What power?
我可以在多元宇宙间旅行
I can travel the Multiverse.
什么？
What?
-你可以以实体形式从一个宇宙穿越到另一个？ -没错
-You can physically move from one universe to another?  -Uh-huh
-怎么办到的？ -这就是问题所在：我也不知道怎么做的
-How?  -That's the problem: I don't know how.
我控制不了它
I can't control it.
只有在我极度恐惧的时候才会发生
Only happens when I'm really, really afraid.
好吧  另一个我知道如何打败那只恶魔吗？
Okay.  Did the other me know how to defeat this demon?
好吧，你只是知道有一本纯善的魔法书
Well, you just knew this magical book of pure good
可以提供给法师击败敌人所需的一切
that gives a sorcerer whatever they need to defeat their enemy.
维山帝之书？
The Book of Vishanti?
那书不是真的
It's not real.
那只是个虚构的童话故事
It's a fairy tale that doesn't exist.
事实上，它真的存在
Actually, it does.
等你成了至尊法师，就会在秘籍中发现它了
I found out in the secret book you get when you become Sorcerer Supreme
真是难以置信……
Unbelievable...
-你不是至尊法师吗？  -是的，我不是至尊法师
-You're not the Sorcerer Supreme?  -No, I'm not the Sorcerer Supreme.
另一个宇宙中的你是至尊法师
Other you was the Sorcerer Supreme in his universe.
尽管它确实存在，
Although it does exist,
维山帝之书据说是不可能拿到的
The Book of Vishanti is said to be unreachable.
它可以
It is.
除了……
Except,
我们刚到那儿，
We reached it.
然后恶魔就追上了我们，
Then the demon caught up with us.
我本以为你会保护我，但是……
I thought you'd protect me, but...
你没有
You didn't.
你是指在我梦中的那场搏斗
That was fighting in my dream.
那不是一个梦
That wasn't a dream.
证明给我看
Prove it.
那并不是梦……
It wasn't a dream...
那意味着……
That means...
梦是窥探我们在多元宇宙中的自我的窗口
Dreams are windows into the lives of our Multiversal selves.
他也是这么说的
That was his theory.
所以，我赤裸身体被一个小丑追杀的噩梦……
So that recurring nightmare where I running naked from a clown...
在某个宇宙中
Somewhere out out there.
是真实发生的
It's real.
在某个宇宙中，我有个马尾辫
Somewhere out there, I had a ponytail.
可能还会有更多的怪物来抓她
There could be more creatures coming for her.
这种力量掌握在一个小女孩手里真够危险  想象一下要是被真正的威胁获得了……
The power is dangerous enough in the hands of a kid.  Imagine if a real threat acquired it.
我突然想到，年轻人，我们还不知道你的名字呢
It occurs to me, young one, we don't know your name.
我叫阿美莉卡·查韦斯
America Chavez
查韦斯小姐，你愿意跟我们回卡玛·泰姬吗？
Miss Chavez, will you come with us to Kamar-Taj?
在那儿你会安全的
You'll be safe there.
我怎么知道你不会像他一样背叛我?
How do I know you won't betray me like he did?
我想你只能选择信任我
I guess you just gonna have to trust me
我们怎么处理他？
What do we do with him?
这样是违反规定的
That's gonna violate an ordinance.
哦，我还埋过更糟的
Oh, I buried worse.
杀死他的怪物,
The creature that killed him, did...
和那只章鱼怪有着同样的记号吗？
have the same markings as the octopus?
是符文
Runes.
那不是一种法术
This isn't sorcery.
是种巫术
It's witchcraft.
你知道有谁面对过这种东西吗？
Do we know anyone who's faced such a thing?
我想我知道
I think I might.
巧克力！
Chocolate!
我是怎么说的？
What did I say?
可是我们等不及啦！
But we can't wait!
我是怎么说的？
Well what did I say?
去洗洗手吧
Go wash your hands.
妈妈，别这样  我们不是小孩子啦
Mom, come on.  I'm too old for that.
-好吧  -你可以帮我盖被子，妈妈
-OK.  -You can tuck me in, mom.
知道吗，
I know.
家人就是一切
A family is forever.
即使想要，我们也永远不可能真正离开彼此
We could never truly leave each other even if we tried.
妈妈，我改变主意了  你可以帮我盖被子
Mom, I changed my mind.  You can come tuck me in if you want.
我爱你们
Love you.
苹果树，对吗？
Apples, right?
终于
Eventually.
-闻起来……  -很香甜
-It smells...  -Sweet.
我觉得还挺逼真的
I was gonna say real.
它们就是真的，谢谢
It's all very real. thanks
-我已经不碰魔法了  -我看的出来
-I put the magic behind me.  -So I can see.
好吧，我就知道你迟早会过来，跟我谈西景镇发生的事
Well... I knew sooner or later you'd show up wanting to discuss what happened at Westview.
我犯了一些错误
I made mistakes,
而且……有人受到了伤害
And... people were hurt
但你最终还是把它纠正了，这一点毫无疑问
but you put things right in the end and that was never in doubt.
我不是来找你谈西景镇的事的
I'm not here to talk about Westview.
-那你来干什么？  -我们需要你的帮助
-Then what are you here for?  -We need your help.
什么事？
With what?
你对多元宇宙了解多少？
What do you know about the Multiverse?
多元宇宙……
The Multiverse.
幻视有套理论，他相信多元宇宙是真实……
Vis had his theories. He believed it was real.
却又……危险的
And...dangerous
好吧，这两点都让他说对了
Well, he was right about both.
我们找到了一个女孩，她能以某种方式穿越宇宙，但她被追杀了……
We found a girl who can somehow travel across it, but she's being pursued.
谁在追杀她？
Pursued by who?
某种恶魔，想把她的力量据为己有
Some kind of demon.  One that covets her power for itself.
现在我们把她带到了卡玛·泰姬
Now, we've taken her to Kamar-Taj.
虽然我们有自己的防御力量
And we've got our defenses,
但是，我们用得上复仇者的帮助
but... we could use an Avenger.
还有其他的复仇者呢
There are other Avengers.
但是，考虑到要在莫霍克发型的弓箭手、几个虫子主题的犯罪斗士
Yeah, but given the choice between the Archer with the Mohawk, and several bug-themed crimefighters,
和这个星球上最强大的魔法师之一之间做选择，
or.... one of the most powerful magic wielders on the planet,
答案显而易见
it's an easy call.
来卡玛·泰姬吧
Come to Kamar-Taj
我们又能把你印在午餐盒饭上了
We'll get you back on a lunchbox.
要是你把阿美莉卡带到这儿呢？
What if you brought America here?
这里？
Here?
是的，我了解这种感觉
Yeah, I know what it's like:
孤身一人，因为你自己也不想要的能力被追杀
To be on your own, hunted for abilities you never wanted.
我可以保护她
I can protect her.
你从没告诉过我她的名字，对吧？
You never told me her name, did you?
是的，我没有
No, I didn't.
要知道，六边形（幻境）是最简单的部分
You know, the hex was the easy part.
撒谎，可没那么容易……
The lying, not so much...
黑暗神书
The Darkhold.
你对黑暗神书很熟悉啊
You're familiar with the Darkhold
我知道这是本诅咒之书，
I know it's the book of the Damned,
还会腐化任何接触过它的人和物
and that it corrupts everything and everyone that it touches.
我想知道它对你做了什么
I wonder what it's done to you.
黑暗神书只是让我看到了真相
The Darkhold only showed me the truth.
我失去的一切
Everything I lost,
都可以复得
can be mine again.
你想从阿美莉卡身上得到什么？
What do you want with America?
你想从多元宇宙中得到什么？
What do you want with the Multiverse?
我要离开这个世界了
I'm going to leave this reality.
去到一个可以和我的孩子团聚的宇宙
And go to one where I can be with my children.
旺达，你的孩子不是真的
Wanda, your children aren't real.
你用魔法创造了他们
You created them using magic.
每个母亲都是这么做的
That's what every mother does.
如果你知道，
If you knew,
有一个宇宙中，
there was a universe,
在那里你很快乐
where you were happy.
你难道不想过去吗？
Wouldn't you want to go there?
我现在就很快乐
I am happy.
我比大多数人更清楚什么是自欺欺人
I know better than most what self-deception looks like.
你想要做的事会公然违反每个自然法则
What you're doing is a flagrant violation of every natural law.
如果你夺走那个孩子的力量，她就会死
If you take that child's power, she won't survive.
我不喜欢伤害任何人，斯蒂芬
I don't relish hurting anyone, Stephen.
但她也不是一个孩子，
But she's not a child,
她可是个超自然生物
she's a supernatural being.
这种强大的力量会对这个以及其他的世界造成伤害
Such raw power could wreak havoc on this and other worlds.
她的牺牲……是为了更伟大的利益
Her sacrifice... would be for the greater good.
那好，你可以和午餐盒饭说拜拜了，因为只有我们的敌人才会找这种借口
Well, you can kiss the lunchbox goodbye, because that's the kind of justification our enemies use.
你不也是这么做了吗？
Is it the one you use?
在你把时间宝石交给灭霸的时候？
When you gave Thanos the Time Stone?
那是在战争时期，而且我是迫不得已
That was war, and I did what I had to do.
你打破了规则，然后成了英雄
You break the rules and become a hero.
我这么做，就成了敌人
I do it and I become the enemy.
这似乎可不公平啊
That doesn't seem fair.
现在你要怎样？
What happens now?
你回到卡玛·泰姬，
Return to  Kamar-Taj,
准备在日落前把阿美莉卡·查韦斯交出来
and prepared to hand over America Chavez by sundown.
和平地
Peacefully.
在那之后……
After that...
你就再也不会见到我了
You'll never see me again.
如果我们不这样做呢？
And if we don't?
那么，来找她的人就不会是旺达了
That it won't be Wanda who comes for her.
而是猩红女巫
It will be the Scarlet Witch.
猩红女巫
Scarlet Witch
旺达已经不在了
Wanda is gone.
她得到了黑暗神书，而黑暗神书控制了她
She's got the Darkhold and the Darkhold has her.
猩红女巫具有深不可测的魔法
Scarlet Witch is a being of unfathomable magic.
她可以凭个人意志改写现实
She can rewrite reality as she chooses,
预言中说，她要么统治宇宙，
and is prophesied to either rule,
要么毁灭宇宙
or annihilate the cosmos.
她凭借意念控制了整个小镇
She took over a whole town using her mind.
如果她得到了阿美莉卡的能力，
If she gets America's power,
就可以奴役整个多元宇宙
She could enslave the entire Multiverse.
所以，你去寻求帮助的那个人，
So the person you went to ask for help,
你告诉了她我的确切位置
and told exactly where I am.
就是她想杀了我？
Is the person that's trying to kill me?
立即停止教学  把学徒武装起来
Suspend teaching at once.  And arm the students.
卡玛·泰姬现在必须成为一个堡垒
Kamar-Taj must now become a fortress.
那些是从香港和伦敦圣殿来的法师
That's the masters from Hong Kong and London Sanctum.
能够在一起同生共死
Honored to face death again by your side.
是我的光荣
这是大家的光荣
The honor is ours.
至尊法师有任何要求，我们都会照做
Whatever the Sorcerer Supreme asks of us, it shall be done.
（鞠躬）这是古老习俗
It's ancient custom.
要审慎选择你的措辞
Choose your words wisely.
-恐怕多元宇宙会命系于此  -我懂
-The fate of the Multiverse may depend on it.  -Got it.
不会有压力的
No pressure then.
这一切都是为了你昨天遇到的那个孩子
All this for a child you met yesterday.
旺达，你的怒火是有情可原的
Wanda, you were justifiably angry.
你不得不做出莫大的牺牲
You had to make terrible sacrifices.
我在我爱的人头上炸了个洞
I blew a hole through the head of the man I love.
结果却毫无意义
And it meant nothing.
不要跟我谈什么牺牲，斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇
Do not speak to me of sacrifice, Stephen strange.
如果你给我想要的东西，
If you give me what I want.
我就把你送到一个，可以和克莉丝汀在一起的世界
I'll send you to a world where you can be with Christine.
整个卡玛·泰姬与你势不两立
The full might of Kamar-Taj stands against you.
进入防御阵地
Defensive positions.
现在
Now
你休想踏入这片圣地
Do not dare to enter these sacred grounds.
你根本不明白，我刚才是多么的理性
You have no idea just how reasonable I've been,
是啊  使用诅咒之书，自称女巫，还召唤怪物来绑架一个孩子？ 我丝毫不觉得这能叫做“理性”
Yeah. Book of the damned, calling yourself a witch, conjuring creatures to abduct a kid?
I don't exactly call that being reasonable.
让那些生物去追她，而不是我亲自上阵，是一种仁慈
Sending those creatures after her instead of myself was mercy.
不管你如何的虚伪和施以侮辱，
And in spite of your hypocrisies and insults,
我已经恳求过你，安全离开，不要挡我的道
I've begged you to safely get out of my way.
现在，我已经耗尽了我的耐心
Here I've exhausted my patience.
但是我真希望你能明白……
But I do hope you understand...
即使是现在，
That even now,
将要发生的事情……
what's about to happen...
这就是我，在保持理性
This is me, be reasonable.
坚持住！
Hold!
搞定了
Nailed it.
加固护盾！
Reinforce the shield!
她在试图入侵他们的头脑
She's trying to get in their heads.
集中精力！
法师们！ 坚定意志！
Sorcerers!  Fortify your mind!
逃吧
Run.
护盾失效了
The shield is down.
开火！
Fire!
好！
Yes!
找掩护！
Take cover!
任意开火！
Fire at will!
王！快离开这儿！
Wong! Get out of here!
你想要那个女孩，必须先过我这关
You want the girl, you'll have to go through me.
好啊
Fine.
我们要带你离开这儿，就现在
We'll get you out of here.  Now.
为什么？  发生了什么事？
Why?  What happened?
卡玛·泰姬已经陷落
Kamar-Taj has fallen.
反射
Reflections.
她在利用反射
She's using the reflections.
把它们盖起来！
Cover them!
你牺牲了这么多条生命，就为了阻止我和孩子们在一起
You gave all those lives, just to keep me from my children.
是你夺走了这些生命
You took those lives.
不能允许你穿越多元宇宙
You cannot be allowed to cross into the Multiverse.
我不是一个怪物，斯蒂芬
I'm not a monster, Stephen.
我是一个母亲
I'm a mother.
旺达，你并没有孩子
Wanda, you have no children.
他们并不存在
They don't exist.
哦，但是在其他任何一个宇宙中，他们都是存在的
Oh, but they do, in every other universe.
我知道他们是存在的
I know they do.
因为我梦见了他们，
Because I dream of them,
夜夜如此
every night.
我的孩子们  我们在一起生活
Of my boys.... Of our life together.
每天晚上做着
Every night.
同样的美梦
The same dream.
每天早上醒来
Every morning,
同样的......噩梦
The same... nightmare.
等你到了他们身边呢？
What if you reach them?
另一个你身上，会发生什么？
What happens to the other you?
那些孩子的母亲身上，会发生什么？
What happens to their mother?
生命法庭的雕像 Living Tribunal Statue World
猛攻峡谷世界 Onslaught Canyon World
致敬詹姆斯·弗兰科的电影《127 小时》
镜子世界 Mirror World
蜂巢世界 Honeycomb World
水下世界 Underwater World
可能是致敬亚特兰蒂斯
变体纽约 Alt New York
注意出租车广告：昆汀的电影《房》上映中
管道世界 Pipe World
出现类似《蜘蛛侠·英雄远征》的无人机
亡灵世界 Post-Apocalyptic World
蛮荒世界 Savage Land
致敬漫威漫画《Savage World》，该世界是X战警中万磁王的故乡
漫画世界 Comic Book World
立方体世界 Cube World
致敬漫威漫画《House of M》
油画世界 Paint World
黑白电影宇宙
可能致敬《蜘蛛侠·平行宇宙》的暗影蜘蛛侠宇宙
你还好吗？
You OK?
你救了我们俩
You save we.
但愿如此
I hope so.
你竟然没吐
Surprised you didn't puke.
这不是我第一次怪异的旅途了，孩子
It's not my first weird trip, kid.
所以，这里是多元宇宙中的另一个纽约
So, this is New York in the Multiverse...
这就来了
There it is.
真糟
Crap
等一下
Cut it out.
是的，你被炸得伤痕累累
Yeah, you got pretty dinged up.
我们会补好你的
We'll get you fixed.
好了，阿美莉卡
All right, America.
你现在得打开一个传送门送我们回去
You got to open a portal that get us back there right now.
我不知道怎么做
I don't know how.
-你刚才不是做到了吗   -不是靠主观意愿
-You just did it.  -Not on purpose.
王被单独留下来和旺达呆在一起，而我是他唯一的希望
Wong is back there alone with Wanda and I'm the only hope he has.
-我没法控制自己的能力  -你必须用某种方式控制它，即使是我都能控制……
-I can't control my powers.  -You must be able to control it somehow, even I could control...
好吧，那么整个宇宙中的你呢？也许她可以控制自己的能力
Well, what about this universe's version of you?  Maybe she could control her powers.
-这个宇宙中没有另一个我  -什么？
-This universe doesn't have a me.  -What?
任何宇宙中都没有
None of them do.
-但你是怎么知道的？ -因为我都看过了
-But how do you know that?  -Because I've looked.
而且……因为我从不会做梦
And... because I never dream.
没关系的，孩子  即使你把我送回去，我也没办法对付旺达
It's OK, kid.  Even if you could get me back there, I have no way of fighting Wanda.
那维山帝之书呢？
What about The Book of Vishanti?
它怎么了？
What about it?
另一个你认为它可以阻止任何追杀我的人
Other you thought it could stop whoever was after me.
是啊，对其他的我来说有用  但他又不在这里，对吧？
Yeah, well, good for other me. He's not here, is he?
我可不知道书在哪儿  所以，除非这儿还有另一个的另一个我……
I don't know where it is.  So unless there's another other me...
我们得去寻找……
We need to go find...
第三个我
Other "other me".
红灯行？
They go on red?
多元宇宙旅行的第一条规则：
Rule No. 1 of Multiversal travel.
你什么也不知道
You don't know anything.
好吧
Right.
变红灯了
It's red.
那么，第二条规则是什么？
So, what's rule No. 2?
阿美莉卡？
America?
规则2：去找吃的
Rule No.2: find food
我最喜欢披萨，披萨球
Preferrably pizza, pizza balls.
那你怎么付钱呢？
How'd you pay for that?
这是免费的   实际上，在大多数宇宙中食物都是免费的
It was free.  Food is free in most universes, actually.
你们那儿还要付钱，真是奇怪
It's weird you guys have to pay for it.
嘿，你还没付钱呢
Hey, you didn't pay for that.
糟了，也许它在这儿不是免费的
Crap. Maybe it's not free here.
披萨老爹向来都是要收钱的
Pizza Poppa always gets paid.
好吧，披萨老爹，放轻松
Alright, pizza Poppa, relax,
-她还是个孩子，饿极了……  -放松你个头，奇异博士
-She is just a kid, we are hungry...  -Relax yourself there, Doctor Strange
话说，你从哪得到这个披风的？ 做的还挺逼真的
Where did you get this cape from anyway?  Oh, that feels authentic.
这不是披风，是斗篷，而且我建议你撒手
It's not a cape, it's a cloak and I suggest you let go.
你从斯特兰奇博物馆搞到了这套衣服，不是吗？
You took this whole suit from the Strange Museum, didn't you?
-斯特兰奇博物馆？  -你是个贼
-Strange Museum?  -You're a taker,
那你为什么不再偷点芥末呢？
Why don't you take some mustard?
走吧，这不是永久性的
Come on, it's not permanent.
它会在几分钟后停止吗？
Is it gonna stop in a few minutes?
大概三周后吧
About three weeks.
我们刚才穿越的那些宇宙，
Those universities we went through,
在其中一个里面，我们是变成了油画吗？
were we paint in one of them?
是啊，你不会想被困在那儿的
Yeah, you don't want to get stuck in there.
没有东西吃
It's really hard to eat.
你造访过多少个宇宙？
How many universes have you been through?
72个？73，把这个也算上的话
72?  73, counting this one.
那真是……
That's...
还真是不少啊
That's a lot.
记忆小路  趁现在，以优惠价格回放你重要的记忆
Memory lane. Replay your significant memories now in a discounted price.
我们替你记忆，你就不会遗忘
We remember, so you don't forget.
这里真是挺不错的
This is pretty fancy.
确定不要再捐一笔助学贷款吗？
Sure you didn't have to take out another student loan?
不了  我不久前卖掉了我们上周手术的那些肾脏中的一个
Nah. I just sold one of those kidneys that we operated on last week.
所以，我想送给你一个小东西
So I... got you a little something.
祝贺你
Congratulation
这是什么？
What is it?
打开看看
Open it and see.
克莉丝汀，这是……
Christine, this is...
这个太棒了  谢谢你
This is amazing. Thank you.
我们没时间看这个了
We don't have time for this.
记忆小路  趁现在，以优惠价格回放你重要的记忆
Memory lane.  Replay your significant memories now in a discounted price.
我们替你记忆，你就不会遗忘
We remember, so you don't forget.
这是在哪？
Where's this?
故乡
Home.
我的妈妈们
My moms.
你是对的，这只是在浪费时间
You were right, this is just a waste of time.
嘿，孩子
Hey, kid.
那就是你第一次打开传送门，对吗？
That was the first time that you opened a portal, right?
这不重要了
It doesn't matter.
这很重要，你失去了两个母亲
It does matter, you lost your parents.
不是“失去”了她们，我害死了她们
I didn't lose them, I killed them.
不  不，你没有  千万不要这样想
No, no, you did not.  Don't even think that.
好吧，我用自己无法控制的力量，打开了一个传送门，
把他们传送到了一个随机的、可能是致命的宇宙，还没办法离开
OK, I opened a portal with the powers I can't control
and sent them to a random, probably deadly universe with no way to escape.
听着，如果你的母亲们和她们的女儿一样……
Listen, if your moms are anything like their daughter...
就能活下来
They survived.
我相信总有一天你会再见到她们
I'm sure you'll meet them again someday.
听起来不坏
Not bad.
谢谢
Thanks.
你记忆库里的那个女人，
That woman in your Memory Lane thing,
就是克莉丝汀，对吗？
that was Christine, right?
是的，那是克莉丝汀  你是怎么知道她的？
Yes, that was Christine.  How do you know her?
从其他的你那里
From other you.
-他们在一起了吗？ -不，他们彼此都不联络了
-Were they together?  -No, they didn't talk anymore.
-你把事情搞砸了  -当然了
-You blew it.  -Of course.
你也是和自己的克莉丝汀搞僵了吗？
Did you blow it with your Christine?
-是的，我想我是  -为什么？
-Yes, I guess I did.  -Why?
-这很复杂  -比被女巫在多元宇宙间追杀还复杂？
-Complicated.  -More complicated than being chased by a witch through the Multiverse?
是的，事实上确实如此
Yes, actually it is.
斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇博士
为打败灭霸献出了生命
我们永远怀念这位地球上最伟大的英雄
-为打败灭霸献出了生命？  -是的，你看，我们并不全是坏蛋
-Gave his life defeating Thanos?  -Yeah, see?  We're not all bad.
如果另一个你已经死了
If other you was dead,
谁是守护圣殿的法师？
Who's master of the Sanctum?
哦，见鬼了
Oh, shit.
-你认识他？  -是的，莫度
-You know him?  -Yeah, Mordo.
他其实是第一个让我进入卡玛·泰姬的人
He's actually the first guy who let me in Kamar-Taj.
-那太好了  -然后他突然变卦，余生致力于谋杀我
-Oh, great.  -And then he snapped and dedicated his life to trying to kill me.
哦，好吧
Oh, great.
我一直猜想这一天会到来
I always suspected this day would come.
-真的？  -没错
-You did?  -Yes.
因为你一直猜想这一天会到来
Because you always suspected this day would come.
好兄弟
My brother.
好吧
All right.
进来，把你的宇宙的一切
Come... and tell me everything...
都告诉我吧
About your universe.
红灯行
We go on red.
你也挺厉害啊，看起来
And you're quite formidable too, it seems.
一个多元宇宙的旅行者
A Multiversal traveler.
感谢你用星星把奇异博士带到了安全的地方
But thank the stars you brought Doctor Strange to safety.
不，我们只是逃掉了，并不意味着我们就安全了
Well, just 'cause we jumped ship， doesn't mean we're safe.
我们的旺达有能力召唤出恶魔和怪物
Our wanda has the ability to conjure demons and monsters
来攻击其他宇宙中的阿美莉卡
to attack America in other universes.
这么说她得到了黑暗神书？
So she has the Darkhold?
-你知道黑暗神书？  -是的，我们这个宇宙中也有一本黑暗神书
-You know about the Darkhold?  -Yes, we have a Darkhold in this universe too.
我把它放在这座圣殿里
I got it here in this Sanctum.
我们绝不能让这么危险的武器落入坏人之手
We would never risk a weapon that dangerous falling into the wrong hands.
太对了
Damn right.
如果你们的黑暗神书和我们的一样，我恐怕她能做到的，远比召唤怪物来追杀你们更糟
If you're dark hole is anything like ours, I'm afraid she can do far worse
than just summoned monsters to come after you, you know.
-你是什么意思？  -有一个咒语，
-What do you mean?  -There is a spell.
在那些书页中，
contained within those pages,
会腐蚀灵魂，
corrosive to the soul,
对现实本身造成亵渎——
A desecration of reality itself.
梦行
Dreamwalking.
使用梦行的法师，可以将自己的意识从他们的宇宙中投射到另一个
A dreamwalking sorcerer projects their own consciousness from their universe into another.
占据另一个自己的身体
Possessing the body of an alternate self.
他们可以操纵这个邪恶的分身，远程追击他们的敌人
Playing puppeteer this unholy doppelganger and pursue their enemies from afar.
这种占有并不能在多个世界之间建立永久的联系
The possession is not a permanent link between realities.
但在他们梦行的短暂时间里
But in the fleeting time they dreamwalk,
他们可能会对所入侵的宇宙造成不可挽回的损害
they can do irreparable damage to the universe they invade.
所以你们要面对的可能不是恶魔
So it may not be a demon that you face.
更有可能是猩红女巫
It may be the Scarlet Witch.
那她为什么不一开始就这么做？
But, why didn't she do that to begin with?
因为那时她还存有理性
Because that was her being reasonable.
你对维山帝之书了解多少？
What do you know of The Book of Vishanti?
它是黑暗神书的反面
The Darkhold's antithesis.
它可以向法师提供所需的任何力量来征服他们的敌人
It can give a sorcerer whatever power they need to vanquish their enemy.
我需要你的帮助……
I need your help to...
我很抱歉，斯蒂芬
I'm sorry, Stephen.
但我希望你能完全理解，
But I hope you, of all people, understand
对我们的世界构成威胁的，并不是旺达·马克西莫夫，
that it is not Wanda Maximoff who threatens our reality,
而是你们两个
It's the two of you.
茶里加了什么？
What is in that tea?
你个王八……
You son of a b...
尼山迪之沙
Sands of Nisanti.
我只是在做你会做的
I'm only acting, as you would.
她要来了
She's coming.
我能再吃点冰激凌吗？ 求你啦
Can I have a little more ice creams?  Please, please.
就一点，求你了
A little more, please, please
-你知道谁是最棒的？  -是谁？  -2003年的
-You know who's best?  -Who?  -2003
老虎队
Tigers.
妈妈？
Mom?
嗯，亲爱的
Yes, sweetheart.
你要去哪儿？
Where're you going?
我只是去扔垃圾
Just to take out the trash.
我们能给你看点东西吗？
Can we show you something?
妈妈，快来啊
Mom! Hurry, come on.
快来呀，这很重要！
Come on, it's important!
妈妈，你会喜欢它的
Mom, You'll like it.
来啊  快来  这个很重要
Come on!  Hurry up!  It's important!
好啦，妈妈，请听这个……
OK, so mom, listen to this...
-我来起头  -不，我想先唱！
-I'm gonna start it.  -No, I wanna start it!
为什么……你们不
Why... don't you both...
一起来...
start it whatever?
唱这个呢？
it is together?
我们像其他孩子一样喜欢冰激凌
We like ice cream like every child should...
如果让我们再来一点冰激凌，
and if we get some ice cream,
我们保证会乖乖的！
We promise to be good!
-你还活着？  -是的
-You're alive?  -Yes.
但还有好多人失去了生命
But so many others were lost.
把我解下来，我得去毁掉那本书
Set me free, I need to destory the book.
不  不能由你来做
No.  It cannot be you.
莎拉
Sara.
妈妈！妈妈！发生了什么？
Mom!  Mom!  What happened?
你还好吗？
Are you OK?
比利？ 汤米？
Billy?  Tommy?
我需要黑暗神书的咒语
I need the Darkhold spells.
你是至尊法师，把你知道的告诉我！
You, are the Sorcerer Supreme, tell me what you know!
你得先杀了我，巫婆
You have to kill me, witch.
不是杀你，而是他们
Not you, them
旺达，停下！
Wanda, stop!
旺达，求你了！
Wanda, please!
那本黑暗神书只是份副本！
The Darkhold was a cope!
一份副本？
A copy?
传说中提到了一座山，你要找的咒语就刻在它的墙上
Legend speaks of a mountain with the wretched spells you seek carved to its walls.
黑暗神书就是在那里被转写下来的
It's there the Darkhold was transcribed.
叫做温达尔冈山
Mount Wundagore
温达尔冈？
Wundagore?
没人能在途中幸存下来
No one has survived the journey.
也许我们会成为例外
Perhaps we will be there exception.
这个宇宙烂透了
This universe sucks.
斗篷？
Cloak?
喂
Hey.
嘿，穿实验服的！ 我们到底是在哪？
Hey, Labcoat!  Where the hell are we?
听着，我不知道你是谁、你对我们来这儿的目的有什么看法，但是……
Look, I don't know who you are?  What you think we're trying to do here, but...
对于你这种无名的科学工作者，当下的情形可不会太妙 所以你就……
these situations don't usually work out well for the nameless scientists.  So just...
克莉丝汀
Christine.
-你好斯蒂芬  -天呐
-Hello Stephen.  -Ay, Dios.
查韦兹小姐
Miss Chavez.
关于你的问题，你们在一个安全等级很高的实验机构中
To answer your question, you are in a highly secure research facility.
你们两人，还有有生命的斗篷，被送到这里用于监视和检测
The two of you along with your sentient cloak are here for surveillance and testing.
-呃，检测？  -嗯，是的，你们是来自另一个宇宙的访客
-Uh, uh, testing?  -Well, yes, you're visitors from another universe.
你们的磁性印迹可能具有放射性
Your magnetic signatures could be radioactive.
你们还可能携带我们无法治疗的疾病
You may be carrying diseases we just don't have treatments for.
因此就有了这些神奇的聚碳酸酯玻璃柜
Hence these amazing polycarbonate fishbowls.
那好，所以我还应该谢谢你喽？
Right. So, I have you to thank for these then.
是的，我用尼山迪之沙研发了这些手铐
Yes, I developed those using the sands of Nisanti.
它是838宇宙的斯蒂芬的魔法遗物之一
One of 838-Stephen's magical relics.
838号斯蒂芬，那是我的某种赛博机器人吗？
838-Stephen, is that some kind of cyborg me?
我们的宇宙是838号
Our universe is 838
而我们将你的指定为616
and we've designated yours 616.
哦，你们肯定对多元宇宙有很多了解  都能派人到处命名宇宙
Oh, you guys sure must know a lot about the Multiverse.  You got someone going around naming realities.
没错
Yes.
至于我，我是巴克斯特基金会的高级研究员，专门从事多元宇宙的研究
Me, I'm a senior phoned the Baxter Foundation and I specialize in Multiversal research.
那么， 不管这儿是什么地方，你是怎么来到这里的呢？
So how do you end up working here, wherever here is?
哦，在你的葬礼上，我自愿来此
Well, I volunteered, at your funeral.
谢谢你能去（我的葬礼）
Thank you for going.
你的伤痕，它们是相似的，但不完全相同，真有意思
Your injuries, they're they're similar, but they're not identical, it's fascinating.
我们在这个宇宙中是什么关系？
What were we to each other in this universe?
我们也从来没完全弄清楚过
We never quite figured that out.
好吧
Yeah.
这还真是我们的共同之处
That's something we got in common.
克莉丝汀
Christine.
你得放我们走
You gotta let us out of here.
-每个人都处在真正的危险之中  听着，我知道你还不了解我……  -我也不想去了解
-Everyone's in real danger.  Look, I, I know you don't know me...  -And I don't want to.
不管我在你的宇宙中对你意味着什么，都不重要
Whatever I was to you in your universe does not matter.
为什么？
Why not?
因为你很危险，斯蒂芬
Because you're dangerous, Stephen.
我的宇宙中有人想得到那个女孩
Someone from my universe wants that girl.
而且她会把这个地方撕成碎片，直到她得到想要的东西
And she's going to rip this place apart, atom by atom, until she gets what she wants.
所以，我不在乎你是来自复仇者还是神盾局……
So I don't care if you're from the Avengers or S.H.I.E.L.D...
我们两者皆非
We're neither.
那是什么？ 九头蛇？
Well, what then?  Hydra?
光照会，想要见你
The Illuminati, will see you now.
光照啥？
The illumi-whati?
别让任何人伤害到这个孩子
Don't let anyone hurt the kid.
我不会有事的
It's gonna be OK.
你不能通过传送门到那上面吗？
You couldn't portal up there?
我的魔法只能带我们到这儿了
My magic can only take us so far.
秘术大师不该踏上温达尔冈的禁区
Master of the Mystic Arts weren't meant to tread upon the forbidden grounds of Wundagore.
很久以前……
Eons ago...
第一个恶魔，西索恩
The first demon,  Chthon,
把他的黑魔法刻在这个坟墓里
carved his dark magic into this tomb.
同样的咒语后来被转写到了黑暗神书上
These same spells, were later transcribed into the Darkhold.
没人知道有哪些没有灵魂的怪物沉睡在里面
There's no telling what soulless monstrosities lie within.
他们一直在等着我
They've been waiting for me.
这不是坟墓
This is't a tomb.
而是王座
It's a throne.
斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇
Stephen Strange.
光照会现召见你
You are now called before the Illuminati.
我，卡尔·莫度男爵，至尊法师，在此……
I, Baron Karl Mordo, the Sorcerer Supreme, hereby...
卡尔？
Karl?
卡特队长
Captain Carter,
第一个复仇者
the first Avenger.
布拉卡格·波尔蒂根，泰瑞根迷雾的守护者，异人族的首领
Blackagar Boltagon, keeper of the Terrigen Mists, the Inhuman king.
布拉卡格·伏特加？
Blackagar Vodka?
嘿，坐在那儿的伙计
Hey the guy in there.
惊奇队长，宇宙守护者
Captain Marvel, defender of the Cosmos.
还有当今最聪明的人
And the smartest man alive,
神奇四侠之一的里德·理查兹
Reed Richards, of the Fantastic 4
你好，斯蒂芬
Hello Stephen.
神奇四侠？ 你们那帮人不是在60年代的音乐排行榜上吗？
Fantastic 4, didn't you guys chart in the 60s?
打断一下，你以为这是闹着玩儿的吗？
I'm sorry, is this a joke to you?
好吧，那边的那家伙头上还顶个叉子呢  所以，是有点儿
Well, there's a guy over there with a fork on his head.  So yeah, a little bit.
你应该庆幸，黑蝠王没有和你交谈
Be grateful, Blackbolt doesn't engage you in conversation.
为什么？  因为他有口臭？
Why?  Does he have bad breath?
这个斯特兰奇甚至比我们的还嚣张
This Strange is even more arrogant than ours.
-不，只是更活蹦乱跳  -就目前而言
-No, just more alive.  -For now.
斯蒂芬，你的到来使现实变得混乱和不稳定
Stephen, your arrival here confuses and destabilizes reality.
你在身后留下的足迹越深，发生入侵的风险就越大
The larger the footprint you leave behind, the greater the risk of an incursion.
-入侵？  -当两个宇宙之间的边界被侵蚀时，入侵就会发生
-Incursion?  -An incursion occurs when the boundary between 2 universes erodes.
然后它们会相撞
And they collide.
将其中的一个或两个宇宙彻底摧毁
Destroying one or both entirely.
另一个你创办了光照会，用来做出别人无法做出的艰难决定
Your alternate self created the Illuminati to make difficult decisions that no one else could.
今天我们将在这里决定如何处置你，还有那个孩子
Today we're here to determine what to do with you and the child.
所以，在我们投票之前，如果你还有什么要紧的话想说
So before we vote, if you got anything serious to say?
-现在就说吧  -我是有话要说
-Now's the time.  -Yeah, I do.
你们担心入侵的话，当真认为我是比猩红女巫更大的威胁？
It's incursions you're worried about. Do you seriously think I'm a bigger threat than the Scarlet Witch?
哦，我们对付的了你的小女巫，如果她使用梦行的话
Oh we can handle you little witch if she decides to dreamwalk.
不，不，你们不能，除非你们给我维山帝之书
No, no you cannot, not unless you give me The Book of Vishanti.
我们感谢你的提醒，斯蒂芬，但我们害怕的不是猩红女巫，
We appreciate your concern, Stephen, but it's not the Scarlet Witch that we fear.
根据我们的经验，对多元宇宙造成最大威胁的人，
From our experience, the greatest danger to the Multiverse, it turns out,
是奇异博士
is Doctor Strange.
你们的奇异博士，地球上最伟大的英雄，为击败灭霸献出生命的那个？
Your Doctor Strange, Earth's mightiest hero who died defeating Thanos?
我们应该把真相告诉他
We should tell him the truth.
我们的最后一位成员
Our final member,
查尔斯·泽维尔教授
Professor Charles Xavier.
-什么真相？  -我们的斯特兰奇不是因此而死
-What truth?  -That's not how our Strange died.
你在思索现在会发生什么
You're wondering what happens now.
不，我已经接受了现实
No.  I had already accepted.
但我确实想知道：
But I do wonder:
既然你可以强迫阿美莉卡把你送到想去的任何一个宇宙
When you could force America to send you to any universe you want.
为什么要把她的能力据为己有？ 你知道这会杀死她
Why take her power for your own?  You know it will kill her.
为了比利和汤米，为了保护他们
For Billy and Tommy, to protect them.
如果他们生病了怎么办？
What if they get sick?
在无限的多元宇宙中，每种疾病都会有治疗的办法
In the infinite Multiverse, there is a cure for every illness.
一个可以解决任何问题的方法
A solution to every problem.
我不能再失去他们一次了
I won't lose them again.
-旺达，不管你怎样努力，都不可能控制一切  -我可以！
-Try as you might Wanda, you cannot control everything.  -I can!
看看你周围
Look around you.
这是刻在石头上面的
It's carved in stone.
我注定要统治一切
I was meant to rule everything.
但那不是我想要的
But that's not what I want.
-我只是想要自己的儿子  -以一个孩子的性命为代价？
-I just want my boys.  -At the cost of a child's life?
一旦被发觉你是得不到安宁的！
There's no peace in knowing that,
尽管你不能和自己的爱子在一起，
Even though you can't be with the ones you love,
但你们还是会在某个宇宙中团聚  难道这还不够吗？
There are worlds where you are together.  Is that not enough?
不行
No.
我们的斯特兰奇不是因抵抗灭霸而死
Our Strange did not die defeating Thanos
战争期间
We were at war.
当我们其他人共同努力试图阻止灭霸的时侯
While the rest of us handed together to try to stop Thanos,
斯蒂芬却总是选择孤军奋战
Steven has always chose to go it alone.
他求助于黑暗神书，开始梦行
He turned to the Darkhold, began dreamwalking,
寄希望于拯救我们的办法藏在多元宇宙中
in hopes that our salvation might lie in the Multiverse.
你猜怎么着？ 并没有，但他还是一意孤行
And guess what?  It didn't, but he kept doing it anyway.
有一天，你把我们召集到一起
One day, you called us all together,
坦白自己一直在梦行
to profess that you've been dreamwalking,
用你自己的话说就是，事态已经失控了
and in your words "things have gotten out hand".
你从来没有告诉我们发生的具体细节
You never told us the details of what had happened,
只是说自己无意中触发了一次入侵
only that you had inadvertently triggered an incursion.
是你，我们的朋友，造成了另一个宇宙的毁灭
You, our friend, had caused the annihilation of another universe.
那个宇宙中的每个人都死了  每一个人
Everyone in that reality died.  Everyone.
斯蒂芬放弃了黑暗神书，甚至帮我们找到了维山帝之书
Stephen renounced the Darkhold, he even helped us find The Book of Vishanti,
我们确实是依靠这件武器击败并杀死了灭霸
a weapon we did use together to kill him, to defeat Thanos.
但是仍然存在最后一个威胁
But one final threat remained.
我会怀念你的，我的朋友
I shall miss you, my friend.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry...
你们告诉克莉丝汀了吗？
Did you tell Christine?
是的
Yes.
雕像，那个雕像是怎么回事？
That statue... what about the statue?
-为什么要建雕像  -这个世界需要英雄
-You built a statue.  -The world needs heroes.
我们做了个艰难的选择，因为我们清楚自己的斯特兰奇的能耐
We made a difficult choice because we knew what our stranger was capable of.
或者说：每一个奇异博士的能耐
Or perhaps, every Doctor Strange is capable of.
这栋建筑已经被攻破了
The building's been breached.
可不是嘛，天才
No shit, genius
状况汇报，调出全部哨兵
Status report, all sentries.
停下！
STOP!
她径直去找那个孩子了
She's headed for the child.
看着他，等我们回来再投票
Watch him, we'll vote on our return.
斯蒂芬，如果你能够逃离这个大厅，你必须去引导阿美莉卡·查韦斯
Stephen, should you manage to escape this Chamber, you must guide America Chavez.
你到底在说什么？
The hell are you saying?
救出那个女孩，然后去找维山帝之书
Save the girl and get to The Book of Vishanti.
-你说什么？ 你这儿有这本书？ -是的，你建立了一个连接点
-What? You have the book here?  -Yes.  You built a waypoint.
-查尔斯，我们不能相信他！  -我相信我们可以
-Charles.  We cannot trust him!  -I believe we can.
那是因为，有人在跌倒后迷失了方向，并不意味着他们就会永远迷失
Just because someone stumbles and loses their way doesn't mean they're lost forever.
我们将会看到，你是什么样的奇异博士
We will see what kind of Doctor Strange you are.
谢谢你
Thank you.
全体哨兵出动
All sentries.
全体疏散
Everybody out!
现在！
Now!
旺达来了
It's Wanda.
奥创命令你……
Ultron command you.
快快快，她要来了
Hurry, hurry, she's coming!
糟了
Oh, no.
旺达，站住
Wanda, stop.
你占有了一个无辜的女人，但你仍然可以做出正确的事：放她走吧
You've possessed an innocent woman, but you can still do the right thing.  Let her go.
请求你
Please.
我自己也有孩子  我能理解你的痛苦
I have children of my own.  I understand your pain.
他们的妈妈还活着吗？
Is their mother still alive?
-是的  -很好
-Yes.  -Good.
还能有人留下来抚养他们
There will be someone left to raise them.
旺达，黑蝠王只需要说句话就能摧毁你
Wanda, Black Bolt could destroy you with one whisper from his mouth.
什么嘴？
What mouth?
带我去找维山帝之书，这样我们就可以一起对付她
Take me to The Book of Vishanti so that we can fight her together.
你没有资格发号施令
You are in no position to give orders.
等他们回来，我的那票还会考虑到这些东西
My vote will conclude these proceedings when they return.
你还没有打够吗？
Haven't you had enough?
我可以打上一整天
I could do this all day.
滚出我的宇宙
Get the hell out of my universe!
他们不会回来了
They're not coming back.
你刚刚已经投出了你的那票：让你的朋友们去死
And you just cast your vote now to kill your friends.
之前还没跟你说过呢
Not that ever bothered you before.
你知道吗，在我那边你仇恨着我
You know you hated me where I came from.
我敢打赌，老兄，在这儿你也暗地里记恨着我
And I bet secretly "my brother" you hated me here.
你一定嫉妒死我了
You must have been so jealous.
知道吗？ 我敢说，当你听说我被腐蚀了一定乐坏了吧！
老天呐，也许一开始就是你把黑暗神书给了我
Do you know what?  I bet you were thrilled When you heard I've been corrupted,
hell, you probably gave me the Darkhold to begin with.
你对这个宇宙，一无所知！
You know nothing, of this universe!
我知道，斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇之死，是让你进入圣殿、成为至尊法师、
I know, the killing Stephen Strange was your ticket to
get in the Sanctum, to becoming Sorcerer Supreme,
还有加入这个由一群马戏团的小丑组成的光照会的门票！
and to joining your little circus of clowns, the Illuminati!
我已经准备好……投出我的这票了……现在！
I'm ready, to cast my vote, now!
受死吧！
Die!
我想我开始明白了
I think we're beginning to understand,
为什么你们的莫度，会那么讨厌你！
why your Mordo, didn't like you very much!
这个锁死了！
You're sealed shut!
后退
Be back.
够了！
Enough!
旺达·马克西莫夫，你的意识正被你的另一个自我挟持
Wanda Maximoff, your mind is being held hostage by your alternative self.
抓住我的手！
Grab my hand!
或许，如果我能把你从废墟下面拉出来
Perhaps, if I can pull you from under the rubble,
咒语就能被打破
the spell should break.
你们还好吗？
Are you all right?
你还好吗？
You're OK?
还好吗？
You're all right?
她把它补好了
She fixed him.
谢谢
Thank you.
泽维尔说我建立了一个通往维山帝之书的连接点  你能带我们过去吗？
Xavier said I built a waypoint to The Book of Vishanti. Can you take us there?
我为什么要相信你？
How am I supposed to trust you?
我知道发生了什么，我对他的所作所为感到抱歉，
但是请相信我，维山帝之书是唯一的解决办法
I know what happened. I'm sorry for what he did, but believe me
The Book of Vishanti is the only way.
是啊，你的方法  你现在的口气像极了我的斯蒂芬
Yeah, your way.  You sound a lot like my Stephen right now.
他必须做那个主刀的人，结果那把刀害死了一兆亿人
He had to be the one holding the knife and then that knife killed a trillion people.
那这个斯蒂芬会不一样吗？
And this Steven is different?
他是
He is.
其他的斯蒂芬是什么样都不重要
It doesn't matter about all the other Stevens.
他和他们不一样
They're not like them.
机灵鬼
Smart kid.
把手伸出来
Give me your hand.
-不要做出让我后悔的事  -我不会的
-Do not make me regret this.  -I won't.
-好了，我们现在可以走了吗？  -跟我来
-OK, can we go now?  -Follow me.
-这条隧道通往哪里？  -通往河底
-Where's that tunnel go?  -Under the river.
快跑！
Go go go!
她去哪了？
Where did she go？
我警告过你
I warned you.
另一个旺达，如果你听得见的话
Other Wanda if you're in there.
屏住你的呼吸
Hold your breath.
-这招杀死她了吗？  -没有，只是为我们争取到了一些时间
-Did it kill her?  -No.  Just bought us some time.
书在这里面，但只有斯蒂芬打开过它
The book's through here, but only Stephen's ever opened it.
肯定是一件对我来说很特殊的东西，只有我自己知道  快啊
A chant only specific to me, something only I would know.  Come on.
斯蒂芬……
Stephen
快想
Come on.
斯蒂芬！
Stephen!
没错
Yeah.
谢谢
Thank you.
芝麻开门
Open sesame.
来吧，孩子
Come on, kid.
你做得到的
You got this.
我们做得到
We got this.
你还好吧？
Are you all right?
这里是裂隙交界处，是各个宇宙之间的空隙
This is the gap junction, the space between universes.
好了
All right, book...
给我所需的东西
Give me what I need.
我的孩子们
My boys.
这不会是你的孩子想要的
This isn't what your children would want.
他们永远不会知道的
They'll never know.
也许他们不会  但你会
Maybe not.  But you will.
哦，糟了
Oh. Crap.
看起来，这个世界在自我坍塌
Looks like this reality collapsed in on itself.
两个宇宙撞到了一起
yeah. Two realities collided.
快来吧
Come on.
阿美莉卡快要没命了
America doesn't have long.
那我们这是要去哪？
So where are we going?
好吧，如果这个宇宙中还有一座圣殿的话
Well, if there's still a Sanctum in this universe.
那里可能还会有第四个我
And there might be another, other, "other me",
而那是我们回到她身边的最好机会
and that's our best shot of getting back to her.
好吧，我终于明白你们那群人为什么这么担心入侵了
Well, I can see why you guys were so worried about incursions.
不管发生了什么
Whatever happened,
这个宇宙中的你，没能很好地阻止它
this universe is you didn't do a very good job of stopping it.
我会把你的话转告给他
I'll tell him you said that.
就停在那儿
Stop at where you are.
你是怎么到这儿的？
How did you get here?
这是个意外
By accident.
你是谁？  或者说，你是什么？
Who are you?  What... are you?
-我只是另一个我们  -来自多元宇宙？
-I'm just one of us.  -From the Multiverse.
没错
That's right.
证明一下
Prove it.
我们有一个妹妹，淹死了
We had a sister, drowned.
在我们还是孩子的时候她就死了
She died when we were kids.
怎么死的？
How?
我们当时…… 在一个结冰湖面上玩耍
We were... playing on a frozen lake.
她掉进了冰窟里
She fell through the ice.
没能救下她
I couldn't save her.
听起来差不多
Sounds about right.
但我们从不会谈这个，对吗？
But we don't talk about that, do we?
是的，我们不谈
No, we don't.
我猜你的世界并不一直是这样吗？
I suppose your reality wasn't always like this?
-我猜这个世界和你的有点像，直到……  -直到什么？
-I suspect it'd be somewhat like yours, until...  -Until?
【根据语法规则，此处不应译为“我迷失了”（I'm lost.)】
直到我输了
Till I lost.
输给谁？
To whom?
你想要什么？
What do you want?
我只是想回家
I just want to get home.
是啊，相信我，我想离开这个地方已经很久了
Yeah, believe me.  I've been trying to leave this place for a long time.
黑暗神书
The Darkhold.
-你守护着这个宇宙中的黑暗神书？  -没错
-You guard the Darkhold in this universe?  -Yeah.
-我有充分的理由  -这是一个开始  我可以利用它
-For good reason.  -That's a start.  I could use it.
-它可以帮我联系上我的宇宙  -要当心
-It can help me to communicate with my universe.  -Careful.
用黑暗神书要付出沉重的代价
The Darkhold exacts a heavy toll.
我并不是冷酷无情，但是对这个地方来说，还剩什么“沉重代价”可付出吗？
I don't mean to be callous, but how much of a heavier toll is there left to exact?
不只是对这个宇宙
Not just on its reality,
还会对阅读它的人
on its reader.
听着，我很遗憾你没能拯救自己的宇宙，但也许你可以帮我拯救我的
Look, I'm sorry you couldn't save your own universe, but maybe you could help to save mine.
你快乐吗，斯蒂芬？
Are you happy, Stephen?
什么？
What?
你快乐吗，斯蒂芬？
Are you happy, Stephen?
那是克莉丝汀·帕尔默
It's the question that...
在她的婚礼上问我的问题
Christine Palmer asked me at her wedding.
我回答说，“是的  我当然很快乐”
I said "Yes. Of course I'm happy".
我是一个拥有神力的法师  怎么可能不快乐呢？
I'm a sorcerer with the power of gods.  What man wouldn't be happy?
然后，我又回到这个该死的闹鬼的屋子里
And then I, came back to this goddamn haunted house.
坐下来，思考自己为什么要撒谎
Sat down, and wondered why I'd lied.
我从不是故意让这些事情发生的
I never meant for any of this to happen.
我要寻找一个不一样的的世界，
I was looking for a world where things were different,
在那里我有克莉丝汀，在那里我很快乐
where I had Christine, where I was happy.
但我就是没找到
But I didn't find it.
我只找到了更多的自己
All I found were more of us.
所以我帮了那些斯蒂芬一个忙
So I did those Stephen a favor.
你有没有做过这样的梦：你在梦中坠落，就像是被人从高楼上推了下来？
Did you ever had that dream where you're falling as if you've been pushed off a tall building?
那个人可能是我
That was probably me.
使用黑暗神书是要付出沉重代价的
The Darkhold exacts a heavy toll.
好吧
OK.
那你更应该别再用它了，让我用一下吧
All the more reason to give it a rest, so let me have it.
做个交易吧  我可以让你用黑暗神书
Here's the deal.  I'll let you use the Darkhold.
前提是你把克莉丝汀给我
If you give me your Christine.
我不认为她会愿意这么做
I don't think she's gonna go for that.
不愿意？  我不这么认为
No?  Didn't think so.
撑住了，我们来了
Hang on, we're coming.
你要用黑暗神书做什么？
What are you doing with the Darkhold?
你要使用梦行？
You're going to dreamwalk?
比梦行还要复杂一点儿
A little bit more than just dreamwalking.
你们斯特兰奇全都是一个样子！
All you Stranges you're the same!
我明白  你说得对
I know.  You're right
我们都是一个样子
We are all the same.
但现在，那孩子需要我  而接下来没有你的帮助，我什么都做不了
But right now, that kid needs me and I can't do any of this without your help.
在我梦行的时候，需要你保护我的身体，以防止他们以擅自闯入为由袭击我
While I'm under, I need you to protect my body in case they attacked me for trespassing.
“他们”是谁？
Who's "they"?
受诅者的灵魂
The Souls of the Damned.
好吧，但难道不是还要有另一个你生活在那个宇宙中，
OK, but doesn't a version of you need to live in that universe,
以供你梦行附体吗？
so that you can dreamwalk into them?
谁说他们必须是活人？
Who said they had to be living?
斯蒂芬·斯特兰奇
Stephen Strange.
占据一具死尸是被禁止的
Possessing a dead body is forbidden!
停止梦行
Cease your dreamwalk.
否则就要面对永恒的后果
Or face the eternal consequences.
斯蒂芬？
Stephen?
它们要把我拉下去了
They are polling me down.
坚持住
Hang on.
邦加利亚斯的火炬
Brazier of Bom'Galiath.
滚回地狱去
Go back to hell.
我抓住你了
I've got you.
你是位秘术大师
You're master of the Mystic Arts.
那些灵魂，利用它们！
Their spirits, use them.
利用它们
Use them.
斯特兰奇！ 哈哈哈
Strange!
梦行！你这个伪君子！
Dreamwalking!  You hypocrite!
这一次，你要想杀了我就不能只杀掉这个我了
This time it's gonna take more than killing me to kill me.
我一点也不想知道
I don't even wanna know.
她快要冲出来了！
She's breaking free!
困住她！
Hold her!
斯特兰奇，吸收阿美莉卡的能力！
Strange, take America's power!
没有别的办法了
There's no other way.
（化用《圣经·以赛亚书》Isaiah 30: 21 This is the way. 这是正路）
这是唯一正途
This is the only way.
我正附在在另一个我的尸体里
It's me, in other me's body.
你想吸收我的能力，不是吗？
You're gonna to take my power, aren't you?
抢在旺达之前
Before Wanda can.
没关系的  我现在能理解了
It's OK.  I understand now.
不，阿美莉卡
No, America.
我是来告诉你要相信自己的
I've come here to tell you to trust yourself.
相信你的能力  只有这样我们才能阻止她
Trust your power.  That's how we stopped her.
-我控制不了它  -不，你可以
-I can't control it.  -Yes, you can.
你向来都是如此  每次你打开传送门，都把我们送到了正好需要的地方
You have been all along.  Every time you open the portal,
you sent us exactly where we needed to go.
那第一次呢？
What about the first time?
即使那次，也将你带到了这一刻
Even that led you to this moment.
你要去揍那女巫的屁股
You're gonna kick that witch's ass.
我抓住你了
I've got you.
我无法打败你
I can't beat you.
但我会给你想要的
I'll give you what you want.
比利  汤米
Billy  Tommy
是个巫婆！
It's a witch!
你都做了什么？！
What have you done?!
妈妈！女巫来了！
Mommy!  Witch!
没事的
It's OK.
我才是你们的母亲！
I'm your mother.
从他们身边滚开！
Get away from them!
不要停
Not yet.
妈妈！不许你靠近我们的妈妈！
Mommy!  Get away from our mom!
-等等  -离远一点……
-Wait  -Get away from...
给我住手！
Stop it!
我永远不会伤害你们，永远不会
I would never hurt you, never.
我从来不想伤害任何人  我不是一个怪物，我是……
I would never hurt anyone.  I'm not a monster, I'm
我是……
I'm...
妈妈，你还好吗？
Mom, are you OK?
不，妈妈，别过去
No, mom, don't go.
会有人爱他们的
Know that you could be loved.
-现在做什么？  -快离开这里
-What now?  -Get out of here.
我们会去找你的
We'll find you.
我们得离开了，现在
We have to go.  Now
黑暗神书由我打开，也必须由我合上
I opened the Darkhold, I have to close it.
再也不会有人被黑暗神书诱惑了
No one will never be tempted by the Darkhold again.
你还好吗？
Are you all right?
-结束了吗？  -是的
-Is it over?  -Yeah.
-阿美莉卡还好吗？  -她正在赶来接我们的路上
-Is America OK?  -She's on her way here to get us.
旺达呢？
Wanda?
不知道
No
看来，她把每一个宇宙中的黑暗神书都摧毁了
So she destroyed the Darkhold in every universe.
她做了正确的事？
She did the right thing?
是的，她做了
Yes she did.
你的宇宙是什么样子？
What's your universe like?
-它很美丽  -嗯
-It's very beautiful.  -Oh.
我希望我可以带你看看
I wish I could show you.
听起来真不错
I really like that.
但我得回去
But I have to go.
是的，我懂
Yeah, I know.
不过，还是很遗憾
It's too bad though.
原本可能发生一次入侵
Could have been one hell of an incursion.
我爱你
I love you.
在每一个宇宙，我都爱你
I love you in every universe.
我也想关心别人或是让别人关心我  我只是……
It's not that I don't wanna care for someone or have someone care for me.  It's just
我害怕了
I get scared.
是的
Yeah.
直面你的恐惧
Face your fears.
奇异博士
Doctor Strange.
嗨  这为啥会比多元宇宙传送门还要难那么多？
Hi, how is this so much harder than Multiversal portal?
她需要慢下来，磨练耐性
She needs to slow down and be more patient.
这让我想起了我的另一个学生
Reminds me of another student I know.
你感觉怎么样？
How are you feeling?
你为什么要问这个？
Why do you ask?
你使用黑暗神书梦行进入了自己的尸体？
You used the Darkhold to dreamwalk into your own corpse?
哦  没错，我是
Oh.  Yeah, I'm right there.
我很好
I'm fine.
但我确实想问你一件事
But I do wanna ask you something.
你快乐吗？
Do you happy?
这真是个……有趣的问题
That's an... interesting question.
我本以为拯救世界会让自己得到快乐，但是……
You'd think that saving the world would get you there, but...
并没有
It doesn't.
有时侯我确实想知道
Sometimes, I do wonder...
我的另一种人生
of my other lives.
但我仍然对当下的生活心存感激
Yet I remain grateful in this one.
即使有种种的磨难
Even with each tribulations.
至少我们不必独自面对它们
We don't have to go through with them.
是的，我们不需要
No, we don't.
等一下
Wait.
-所以  -所以？
-So.  -So?
我划出了点儿火花
Made some sparks.
很好
Great.
你的母亲们会为你骄傲的
Your parents would be proud.
我希望有一天你能展示给她们看
I hope you'll get to show them one day.
斯蒂芬
Stephen.
我很高兴能落入你的宇宙
I'm glad I fell into your universe.
我也是，孩子
So am I, kid.
我也是
So am I
奇异博士？
Doctor Strange?
我能为你做什么？
Can I help you?
你引发了一次入侵  我们得去修补它
You caused an incursion, and we are gonna to fix it.
除非你怕了
Unless you're afraid.
一点也不
Not in a least.
结束了！
It's over!